<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Pions 12</string>
    <string name="bienvenu">WELCOME TO THE GAME</string>
    <string name="commencer">Start</string>
    <string name="titre_nouvelle_partie">New Game</string>
    <string name="joueur2b">Player 1 : White</string>
    <string name="joueur2r">Player 1 : Red</string>
    <string name="joueur2m">Player 1 : Brown</string>
    <string name="humain">Human</string>
    <string name="joueur1n">Player 1 : Black</string>
    <string name="odinateur">Computer</string>
    <string name="bt_jouer_nouvelle_partie">Play</string>
    <string name="text_diffculteF">Level: EASY</string>
    <string name="text_diffculteM">Level: MEDIUM</string>
    <string name="text_diffculteD">Level: DIFFICULT</string>
    <string name="ordiVSordiToast">One of the players must be human</string>
    <string name="annuler">Undo</string>
    <string name="nouvelle_partie">New game</string>
    <string name="rougeCommence">Red begins</string>
    <string name="blancCommence">White begins</string>
    <string name="noirCommence">Black begins</string>
    <string name="a_propos">About</string>
    <string name="titrePopupFin">Game Over</string>
    <string name="effetsSonores">Sound Effects</string>
    <string name="musique">Music</string>
    <string name="langue">Language</string>
    <string name="themePlateau">Board theme</string>
    <string name="classique">Classic</string>
    <string name="Plateaublanc">White</string>
    <string name="bois">Wood</string>
    <string name="themePion">Pawn Theme</string>
    <string name="NoirBlanc">Black and White</string>
    <string name="noirRouge">Black and Red</string>
    <string name="marronCommence">Brown begins</string>
    <string name="noirMarron">Black and Brown</string>
    <string name="leJeu12pions">The Pions 12 game</string>
    <string name="aVousJouer">It\'s your turn</string>
    <string name="tourDeNoir">Black\'s turn</string>
    <string name="tourDeBlanc">White\'s turn</string>
    <string name="tourOrdi">Hmm my turn ...</string>
    <string name="tourDeRouge">Red\'s turn</string>
    <string name="tourDeMarron">Brown\'s turn</string>
    <string name="finDuJeu">Game Over</string>
    <string name="partieEgale">Stalemate</string>
    <string name="blancGagne">White won</string>
    <string name="rougeGagne">Red won</string>
    <string name="marronGagne">Brown won</string>
    <string name="noirGagne">Black won</string>
    <string name="tuAsPerdu">You lost</string>
    <string name="tuAsGagne">Well done !!\n You have won</string>
    <string name="francais">French</string>
    <string name="anglais">English</string>
    <string name="wolof">Wolof</string>
    <string name="aide">Help</string>
    <string name="retourner">Flip</string>
    <string name="reglesDujeu">Rules of the game</string>
    <string name="titreMateriel">Game material</string>
    <string name="titreDeplacement">The movement of the pawns</string>
    <string name="titreCouronement">The crowning of the pawns</string>
    <string name="titreFinPartie">The end of the game</string>
    <string name="copyrignt">Abdou KANJI | 2020 © All rights reserved</string>
    <string name="txtMateriel">The game is played on a board of 25 equal squares. Before starting a game, the 10 black pawns and the 10 white pawns are placed on the first two rows of each player. The two pawns are placed in the middle row on the right side of each player. Only the square in the center of the board is empty at the start. The player who starts the game must land his first move in this square. You can reverse the arrangement of the black and white pawns according to the color chosen by each player.</string>
    <string name="txtDeplacement">There are two types of pieces: pawns and queens.  A pawn must move forward and to the sides, from one square to an empty square in the next row. Movements on non-aligned squares (diagonals) are not allowed.  A queen moves in all directions on successive free spaces in the horizontal or vertical that she occupies. It can land on a distant free square, beyond free squares aligned to its position.</string>
    <string name="txtCouronnement">A pawn becomes a Queen when it reaches the first row of its opponent, the pawn is crowned.  Also when a player has only one piece on the board, then that pawn becomes a queen and she can move in all directions.</string>
    <string name="titrePrise">The capture</string>
    <string name="txtPrise">The capture of the opponent\'s pieces is carried out horizontally and forward, for the pawns. The Ladies are the exception because they can capture in all directions. When a capture has taken place, only the crossed opposing piece is removed from the board.  There are three kinds of holds in Pawns 12: the simple hold, the scoop and the standstill.  A pawn can make a simple take when it is in the presence of an opponent\'s piece behind which is a free square, it can jump over this piece and occupy the free square.  A queen can jump directly or away from an opponent\'s piece, provided they are on the same line.  The raid by a pawn: A pawn can capture several pieces successively depending on the arrangement of the free squares while respecting the movement and simple capture of the pawns.  The roundup by a queen: the principle is the same as that of the simple pawn. The only difference is that the Queen can jump several free squares to capture in all directions.  A roundup must be clearly indicated, piece by piece, by placing the grabber piece on the jumping square, the time to spend there, and by placing this piece on the terminal square.  In the situation where the pieces to be taken are in equal number in two or more possibilities of taking or rounding up, the player is free to choose one of these possibilities.  The taking of the greatest number of parts is priority. The taking confers no priority and imposes no obligation. The player may not take a hold if he wants to or if he doesn\'t notice it.  In this case, if his turn has passed, the opponent before taking his turn may remove from the board the pawn or queen who was to make an unfinished hold or raid, which is called a hold in place. If the player could make two holds in two different places and he chooses one, the opponent will not be able to remove the other piece, the hold in place is canceled. Otherwise he has the choice to remove any piece that should make a capture, the opponent also if he wants or if he does not notice, he has the choice not to remove this piece and play his turn.</string>
    <string name="txtFinPartie">The end of the game is considered equal when there is only one piece left for each player and the player who must make a move cannot capture the other: the game is drawn.  A player wins a game when his opponent has no more pieces on the board.</string>
    <string name="commentDeplacer">"How to move the pieces? "</string>
    <string name="txtFaireUnDeplacementC">- Click on a pawn: if it is your turn, the pawn will be selected and the squares it can reach are marked with green dots. Then click on the valid boxes to move the selected pawn.</string>
    <string name="commentFairePrise">How to take a capture?</string>
    <string name="txtPriseDD">There are also two ways to take holds:  \n- In Drag and Drop mode: do the same to move the pawn, if your finger crosses an opposing pawn, this pawn is automatically removed from the board. If there is a possibility of a raid, do not let go of the pawn and continue to take holds with the same principle until movement is blocked or when you want to stop the raid. Note that only this mode allows you to do a roundup. But be careful when you round up with a queen, as soon as you cross an opposing pawn and your finger arrives on the next free square, the capture is automatically made and your queen remains in this square, if you want to put the queen in another free space, do not run your finger over the free spaces that you reach first.</string>
    <string name="txtPriseC">- In Click mode: once the pawn has been clicked, the marking of valid boxes with green dots lets you know if there is a possibility of making a hold. If you click on a valid square and the pawn crosses another opponent\'s pawn, the capture will be made. Warning ! This mode does not allow you to do a roundup. If it\'s your turn, to capture an opponent\'s pawn that had a chance to take a capture and didn\'t, click on that pawn it will be removed from the board.</string>
    <string name="txtDivers">Click on the return button to change the layout of the pieces on the board. When there are irregularities you can cancel a trip by clicking on the cancel button. For more details I urge you to read the rules of the game in About, they are simple !!</string>
    <string name="description">Pawns 12 also called \"Wouré\" is a combinatorial strategy game from West Africa. It is mainly played in Senegal. This simple game from the same family as the Yoté game is a variation of the Checkers game, the rules are not very similar. This is a very popular and much played game, partly because of its simple rules.  Traditionally in Senegal, Pawn 12 is often played with simple pebbles or sticks constituting the pawns, holes are dug on the ground or lines drawn on a support to form the board. The game is played on a square board divided into 25 equal squares of the same color. At the start of a game both players each have 12 pawns. Each dozen of colors is the property of one day. Usually players choose the colors black and white. The object of the game is to capture all the opposing pawns.</string>
    <string name="txtFaireUnDeplacementDD">There are two ways to move the pieces on the board:  - Drag and drop: make a long press on a pawn, if it is yours automatically the pawn rises, drag it to the square where you want to put it. Once the square marked green, let go of the pawn to make the move and your turn is over, if the square is red the pawn returns directly to its starting position on the board.</string>
    <string name="appliquerLangue">Reopen the app to change the language</string>

</resources>